Guide to the Portland Reporter Photographs Collection 1960-1964
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Portland Reporter photographs collection
1960-1964
Oregon Historical Society, Davies Family Research Library
Org. Lot 62
Portland Reporter Publishing Co., Inc.
49.37 cubic feet 127 boxes, 1 oversize box and 21 oversize folders
The photograph morgue of a newspaper published from 1960-1964 by unions that struck the two primary Portland newspapers, the Oregon Journal and the Oregonian.
Historical Note
The Portland Reporter newspaper was born out of a long and bitter strike by union workers against the Samuel Newhouse-owned Oregonian, a morning paper, and the Oregon Journal, an afternoon newspaper controlled by trustees of the founding Jackson Family. The striked started in November 1959, and the unions launched the Portland Reporter as a weekly on Feb. 11, 1960. It went semi-weekly April 12, 1960, and daily (except Sunday) on Feb. 11, 1961. At its height, circulation reached 78,000 in spite of the fact that the two dailies continued to publish using non-union labor. In August 1961, Newhouse bought the Oregon Journal and moved it into his Oregonian plant. The Portland Reporter generated national attention for its challenge to Portland's newspaper monopoly until it folded in October 1964. Strikers continued to picket the dailies until April 4, 1965, but the Newhouse monopoly had essentially broken the strike long before.
A few months after the Portland Reporter started publishing, it moved into an old brick building at 1714 NW Overton Street after the labor unions refurbished it for their newspaper's new home. The building still stands in Northwest Portland as of 2004.
The Portland Reporter photograph morgue contains photographs taken for and published in the newspaper that depict events of local, national, and international importance from 1960-1964. Subjects include images of the important people and events on local, national, and international scenes, including Portland and Oregon politics; the tsunami that hit the Oregon coast in 1964; the John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson years; John F. Kennedy's assassination; the space race; the Vietnam War; and the Cold War, among many other subjects. Other images document daily life and incidents in Portland and surrounding communities. The local materials were produced primarily by Portland Reporter staff photographers, and some images were obtained from other local sources. National and international images are primarily from the Associated Press wire service. The collection also includes a small quantity of negatives, mostly from non-staff photographers, and some art work and printed materials, most notably a series of Bill Mauldin syndicated cartoons.
All of the photographs in this collection are black-and-white. Most images that appeared in the newspaper are date stamped and have newsprint clippings of captions or brief articles glued to the verso.
The collection is arranged into three series that generally follow the original order:
Series A: Subject Files, 1960-1964
Series B: People Files, 1960-1964
Series C: Bill Maldin Cartoons and Other Printed Material, 1960-1964
The collection is open to the public.
Guimary, Donald Lee. The Decline and Death of the Portland Daily Reporter. Master's thesis. Eugene, OR: University of Oregon, 1966.
Hoffard, Allen Edward. An Experiment in Publishing: The Portland Daily Reporter. Master's thesis. Washington, D.C.: American University, 1964.
Meeker, Richard H. S.I. Newhouse and the Business of News. New Haven and New York: Ticknor & Fields, 1983.
The Oregon Historical Society Research Library has a partial run of the Portland Reporter on microfilm (Feb. 11, 1960-June 19, 1962). The University of Oregon Library has a full run on microfilm. The Oregon Historical Society Sound Recording Collection includes a news commentary by Edward P. Morgon on the newspaper and labor issues, May 1961 (SR 9008).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973--Photographs.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Photographs.; Mauldin, Bill, 1921-2003.
Portland Reporter Publishing Co.
Portland (Or.) --Photographs.
Cold War.; Government and the press.; Journalism--Political aspects --Photographs.; Journalism, pictorial.; Newspapers--Oregon--Portland.; Photojournalism.; Tsunamis--Oregon --Photographs.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Mass media and the conflict.; War photography.
Oregon; Portland; Photographs; Journalism; Government and Politics
Cartoons (humorous images).; Photographic prints.; Film negatives.
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Subject Files, circa 1900-1965; 1960-1965; Series A
  The folders in this series are arranged in the original alphabetical order, and within that order chronologically.
  - Automobiles
    - Automobile accidents, 1960 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Automobile accidents, 1961 (Box-folder 1/2-3)
    - Automobile accidents, 1962 (Box-folder 1/4-5)
    - Automobile accident, 1963 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Automobile accident [negatives only No. 62-1, 2), 1963 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Automobile accidents, 1964 (Box-folder 1/8-9)
    - Automobile accidents, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Automobile caburators, 1962 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Automobile driving records, 1964 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Automobile licenses, 1963 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Automobile parking lot, 1904 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Automobile racing, 1963 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Automobile racing, 1964 (Box-folder 1/16-17)
    - Automobile seatbelts, 1961 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Automobile seats, 1963 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Automobile shows, 1960; 1962 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Automobile tournament, 1964 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Agencies—Marv Tonkin Motors, 1963 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Agencies—Ron Tonkin—Fire damage, 1961 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Amphicar, 1962 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Antiques, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Aston Martin, 1962 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Austin, 1961 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Autin Healey, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Avanti, 1962 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - British Motor Corporation, 1964 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - BMW, undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Buick (also Wildcat), 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Cadillac, 1963 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Chevrolet, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Chrysler, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Citroen, 1961 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Cobra, 1963 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Comet, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Cortez, 1964 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Corvair, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Corvette, 1962 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - DKW, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Datsun, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Dodge, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Fairlane, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Firebird, 1962 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Ford, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Fury, 1962 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Hillman, 1962 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Hot rods, 1960 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Imperial, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Jaguars (Cascade Sports Car Club--people), 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Jeep, 1962 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Low cars, 1962 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Land yachts, 1964 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Lincoln-Mercury, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Continental, 1964 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Lotus, 1961 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - MG, 1963 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Marathon, 1962 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Mercury, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Mercedes Benz, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Mobile safety testing unit, 1964 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Manza-Sprint, 1961 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Mustang, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Nova, 1961 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Oldsmobile, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Plymouth, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Police, 1964 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Pontiac, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Porsche, 1961; 1964 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Rambler, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Renault, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Rolls Royce, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Simca, 1962 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Sprite, 1962 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Stuart, 1962 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Studebaker, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Sunbeam (Joce Kay, Edie Adams), 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Tempest, 1962 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Toyata, 1964 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Triumph, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Thunderbird, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Used car lot--Iverson's, 1964 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Valiant, 1961 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Volkswagon, 1960-1961; 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Volvo, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Automobiles, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Auto tutor machine, 1962 (Box-folder 3/34)
  - Aviation
    - Accidents, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 4/1)
      Dr. Philip M. Rogers, Max L. Terzenbach, Mrs. Eva Berry.
    - Air Force, 1962 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Air Force—304th Air Rescue Squad, 1962 (Box-folder 4/3)
      Maj. Norman Happle, Cmdr. Glenn H. Lathrop (Seattle)
    - Air Force Reserve—313th Squadron, 1962 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Air National Guard, 1961 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Blimp (Mayflower, Goodyear), 1962 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Boeing, 1962 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Civil Air Patrol, 1962 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Flying Farmers (Mrs. John Teufel), 1964 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Flying Tigers, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Frontier Airlines, 1964 (Box-folder 4/11)
      Princess Teresa Hanway, Don McCallum, Dollie Caylor (stewardess)
    - Japan Air Lines, 1963 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Navy, 1961 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Powder Puff Derby, 1962 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Russian and British, 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - United Air Lines, 1963 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Women, 1963 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Avocado trees (Wiggins, Mrs. Paul), 1960 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Babies, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 4/19)
    Dorothy Marie Lui (Seattle), Daniel Rickman, Robert Lee Stevenson, Myrna Strong (nurse), Mrs. Charles Harris (nurse), Eleanor Dash (nurse).
  - Babies—Quadruplets, 1961 (Box-folder 4/20)
    Cutaiar quadruplets (Philadelphia), Feyre Quadruplets (Holyoke, MA)
  - Baby bottles, 1961 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Bagpipes, 1962 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Baker, Oregon—United States National Bank of Oregon, Baker branch, 1960 (Box-folder 4/23)
    Ken Nichols drawing
  - Balloons, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Bands, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 4/25)
    Includes Hillsboro High School; band from Valentine, Nebraska.
  - Bands—Clan Mcleay, 1962 (Box-folder 4/26)
  - Bands—High school, 1963 (Box-folder 4/27)
    State band, John Marshall band
  - Banff, Canada, 1961 (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Banfield Industrial Park (clipping only), 1963 Dec. 23 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Banks
    - Bank robbery, 1963 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - Benjamin Franklin Savings and Loan, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - The Community Bank, 1964 (Box-folder 4/32)
    - Eastport Plaza—Robbery (U.S. National Bank), 1963 (Box-folder 4/33)
    - Eugene, 1960 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - First National Bank of Oregon—Branches, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 4/35)
    - Oregon Bank, 1964 (Box-folder 4/36)
    - Oregon Mutual Savings, 1963 (Box-folder 4/37)
    - Portland Federal Savings, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/38)
    - Seaside, U.S. National Bank of Portland, 1962 (Box-folder 4/39)
    - Security Bank of Oregon, 1964 (Box-folder 4/40)
    - U.S. National Bank, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4/41)
    - Willamette Savings and Loan Association, 1964 (Box-folder 4/42)
  - Barges, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 4/43)
  - Bathing suits, 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 4/44)
  - Baton twirling—Kelly Kadets, 1960 (Box-folder 4/45)
  - Bayshore—Wendell West Company, 1963 (Box-folder 4/46)
  - Beach, Oregon, 1963 (Box-folder 4/47)
  - Beall Pipe and Tank, 1963 (Box-folder 4/48)
  - Beaverton, Or., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/49)
    Contains Value Mart, Bel-Aire Garden Court Apts., Beaveton Elks Lodge, Beaveton Home for Retarded Children.
  - Beds, 1961 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Beatles (teenagers immitating the original Beatles), 1964 (Box-folder 5/2)
    For Beatles singing group, see "Music—Beatles"
  - Bees, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Beetles, Japanese, 1964 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Beirut, Lebanon, 1964 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Belgium—Ghent, 1964 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Bells, 1961 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Benches, 1963 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Bend, Or., 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Berg, Charles F., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Berlin, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Bermuda, 1961 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Berries, 1961 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Best's Store, 1960 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Bible, 1961; 1964 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Bicycles, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Bierstube, 1963 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Billboards, 1960; 1964 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Birds
    - Birds, 1964 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Bluebirds, 1963 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Cranes, 1962 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Crows, 1962 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Ducks, 1961; 1962 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Eagles, 1962 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Gannets, 1961 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Geese, 1962; 1963 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Cooney, 1962 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Mynah, 1960 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Nests, 1961; 1963 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Ostrich, 1962 (Box-folder 5/30)
    - Owls, 1962; 1963 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - Parakeets, 1962 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Peacocks, 1961; 1962 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - Penguins, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - Pheasants, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/35)
    - Pigeons, 1961 (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Quail, 1961 (Box-folder 5/37)
    - Robins, 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 5/38)
    - Sea gulls, 1961 (Box-folder 5/39)
    - Turkeys, 1960; 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5/40)
  - Black Watch, 1963 (Box-folder 5/41)
  - Blanchet House, 1961; 1963 (Box-folder 5/42)
  - Blitz-Weinhard [Brewery], 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/43)
  - Blind, 1964 (Box-folder 5/44)
  - Bloodmobile, 1962 (Box-folder 5/45)
  - Blossoms, 1960 (Box-folder 5/46)
  - Blue Cross, 1962 (Box-folder 5/47)
  - Blue Lake [Or.], 1961 (Box-folder 5/48)
  - Boardman Industrial Park, 1964 (Box-folder 5/49)
  - Boats
    - Boats, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5/50)
    - Boat accidents, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Boat engines, 1961 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Ferry, 1961 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Hydrofoil, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Model boat racing, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Mansion Belle, 1961 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - P, 1962 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Pleasure, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Boat racing, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Boat show, 1961; 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - S, 1963 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Sailboats, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 6/12-13)
    - Stern wheeler, 1964 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Tugboats, 1961 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Turbocraft, 1961 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Yacht, 1961 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Body (dead), 1961; undated (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Bogota, Colombia, 1960 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Bohemians (singing group), 1961 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Bombs, atomic, 1961 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Bones, 1961 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Bonneville Dam, 1961 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Bonneville Power Administration, 1962 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Bookmobile, 1963 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Books, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Borden Chemical, 1961 (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Bottles, 1960; 1964 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Boys clubs, 1963 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Boy Scouts, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 7/3-5)
  - Boy Scouts— Camping, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Boy Scouts—Explorers, 1963 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Bread, 1962 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Bridges
    - Astoria—Megler, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Broadway, 1961 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Burnside, 1961 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Clackamas River, 1961 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Columbia River (Astoria), 1961 (Box-folder Oversize B1/1)
    - Covered—Mohawk River, undated (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Fremont, 1962 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Fremont (rendering of proposed—not built), 1964 (Box-folder Oversize B1/2)
    - Hawthorne, 1962 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Highway 101, 1961 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Highway 101, 1961 (Box-folder 128/1)
    - Hood River, 1962 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Intersate, 1962 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Marquam, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Milwaukie, 1961 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Morrison, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Oregon City, 1964 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Outside of Oregon, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Ross Island, 1962 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Sam Hill (Biggs Junction), 1963 (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Sellwood, 1960 (Box-folder 7/26)
    - St. Johns, 1962 (Box-folder 7/27)
    - St. Johns, 1962 (Box-folder Oversize B1/3)
    - Steel, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 7/28)
    - Troutdale, 1963 (Box-folder 128/1)
    - Vista, 1960; 1962 (Box-folder 7/29)
  - British Trade Festival, 1962 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Brookings, Or., 1962 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Broughton Lumber Company, 1961 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Brownsville, Or., 1964 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Bucket, 1963 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Buddhas, 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Building collapse—Dugout Restaurant, 1962 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Building construction--Copeland Lumber, 1963 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Buildings
    - Buildings, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - A, 1963 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - B, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - C, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Century, 1964 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - D, 1649 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - E, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - F, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Forestry (1906), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/17)
    - G, 191; 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/18)
    - H, 1964 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - I, 1963 (Box-folder 8/20)
    - J, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 8/21)
    - K, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - L, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Lake Osego, 1964 (Box-folder 8/24)
    - M, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 8/25)
    - N, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - O, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/27)
    - P, 1961; 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/28)
    - Portland, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Portland, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 128/2)
    - Portland, 1964 (Box-folder Oversize B1/4)
    - R, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/30)
    - S, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8/31)
    - St. Johns, 1964 (Box-folder 8/32)
    - Standard Insurance, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - T, 1961; 1963 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - W, 1963 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Bull Run, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Bull Run, 1961; 1964 (Box-folder Oversize B1/5)
  - Bulldozers, 1961 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Bullets, 1962 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Burma, 1961 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Buses, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Buses—Portland, 1960-1961; 1963 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Buses—Trailways, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Business Education Day, 1961 (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Cable cars, 1963 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Camellias, 1960 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - Cameron Book Store, 1962 (Box-folder 9/14)
  - Camp Bonneville, 1964 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Camp Collins, 1960 (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Camp Fire Girls, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Camp—Kiwanis Club, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Camp—Lowami, 1964 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Camp—Nomanu, 1962 (Box-folder Oversize B1/6)
  - Camp Meehan, undated (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Camp Perry's sports camp, 1964 (Box-folder 9/21)
  - Camp Rilea, 1961 (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Camp Trestle Glen (Salvation Army), 1961 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - Camp Westwind, 1960 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Camp Wind Mountain, 1963 (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Camp Withycombe, 1963 (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Campbell memorial, 1962 (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Camper, 1964 (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Camping, 1961 (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Canadian Mounted Police, 1963 (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Canby, Or., 1961 (Box-folder 9/31)
  - Candle, 1964 (Box-folder 9/32)
  - Canine Country Club, 1960 (Box-folder 9/33)
  - Cannon, 1964 (Box-folder 9/34)
  - Cantaloupe, 1961 (Box-folder 9/35)
  - Cape Canaveral, Fla., 1961 (Box-folder 9/36)
  - Cape Kiawanda—Pacific City, Or., 1961 (Box-folder 9/37)
  - Capitol Building, 1963 (Box-folder 9/38)
  - Capitol Manor, 1962 (Box-folder 9/39)
  - Capri, 1962 (Box-folder 9/40)
  - Car—Camp Co., 1963 (Box-folder 9/41)
  - Cards (gambling), 1962 (Box-folder 9/42)
  - Carnation Milk, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 9/43)
  - Cartoons, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 9/44)
  - Carving, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 9/45)
  - Carving--Stone carvings, 1961 (Box-folder 9/46)
  - Cascade College, 1960 (Box-folder 9/47)
  - Cascade Locks, Oregon, 1964 (Box-folder 9/48)
  - Cattle, 1962 (Box-folder 9/49)
  - Cave-ins, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 9/50)
  - Cedar Mills (Marlene Village), 1962 (Box-folder 9/51)
  - Cement workers, 1961 (Box-folder 9/52)
  - Cemeteries, 1961 (Box-folder 9/53)
  - Cemeteries—Arlington, Virginia, 1961 (Box-folder 9/54)
  - Cemeteries—Memorial Gardens, 1961 (Box-folder 9/55)
  - Census, 1960 (Box-folder 9/56)
  - Central City, Colo., 1962 (Box-folder 9/57)
  - Ceramic, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9/58)
  - Chairs, 1962 (Box-folder 9/59)
  - Chamber of Commerce—Information Center, 1960 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Chameleons, 1960 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Chariot racing, 1961 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Chase Bag Company, 1962 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Cherry Sweetheart, 1961 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Cheese, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Chickens, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Chico's Pizza Parlor, 1961 (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Children, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 10/10-11)
  - Children's Farm Home, Corvallis, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Children's Home, 1961 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Chiloquin, Oregon, 1961 (Box-folder 10/14)
  - China--Documentary, 1961 (Box-folder 10/15)
  - Chinatown, San Francisco, 1964 (Box-folder 10/16)
  - Chinese, 1962 (Box-folder 10/17)
  - Choir, Swedish, 1964 (Box-folder 10/18)
  - Christie School, 1960 (Box-folder 10/19)
  - Christmas, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 10/20-23)
  - Christmas—Fred Meyer, 1960 (Box-folder 10/24)
  - Christmas—Santa Claus, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Christmas Seals, 1964 (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Christmas trees, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 10/27)
  - Churches
    - Churches, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 10/28)
    - American Church Union (letter only), 1939 Apr. 20 (Box-folder 10/29)
    - Apostolic Faith, 1962; 1964 (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Assemblies of God, 1961 (Box-folder 10/31)
    - Bahai Temple, 1961 (Box-folder 10/32)
    - Baptist—Chinese Baptist, 1963 (Box-folder 10/33)
    - Baptist—Grant Park Baptist, 1964 (Box-folder 10/34)
    - Baptist—First Trinity, 1961 (Box-folder 10/35)
    - Beavercreek—Bryn Seion, 1962 (Box-folder 10/36)
    - Buddhist, 1962 (Box-folder 10/37)
    - Canby, 1961 (Box-folder 10/38)
    - Catholic, 1964 (Box-folder 10/39)
    - Catholic—Chancery, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/40)
    - Catholic—Immaculate Heart, 1963 (Box-folder 10/41)
    - Catholic—St. Lawrence—Fire, 1960 (Box-folder 10/42)
    - Catholic—St. Mary's Cathedral, 1961 (Box-folder 10/53)
    - Catholic—St. Patrick's, 1961 (Box-folder 10/44)
    - Christian—Central, 1962 (Box-folder 10/45)
    - Christian—First, 1962 (Box-folder 10/46)
    - Christian Science, 1960; 1964 (Box-folder 10/47)
    - Christian Science—First Church, 1960 (Box-folder 10/48)
    - Church of Religious Science, 1962 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Congregational—First, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Congregational—Highland, 1964 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Episcopal, 1961; 1963 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Episcopal—All Saints, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Episcopal—St. Aidens, 1962 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Episcopal—St. Barnabas, 1963 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Episcopal—St. Peter's, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Episcopal—St. Stevens, 1964 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Episcopal—Trinity, 1961 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Eugene—Westminster Presbyterian, 1962 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Evangelical United Brethren, 1962 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Garden Home, 1962 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Gresham First Baptist, 1962 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Interchuch Office Center, 1962 (Box-folder 11/15)